{
    "id": "537c63d61fa44674bdb78014d590149c",
    "title": "Intermediate Level Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "She is tired ……………… hungry.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "as well as",
                "or",
                "but"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I hope you ……………………. hard in future.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "work",
                "would work",
                "will work"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Change into exclamatory sentence. The stars are very beautiful.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "How beautiful are the stars!",
                "What beautiful the stars are!",
                "How beautiful the stars are!"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Speak the truth …………………. will help you.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "what",
                "that",
                "when"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "We cannot take back spoken words. Change into passive.",
            "description": "The passive form of cannot take is cannot be taken. ",
            "answers": [
                "Spoken words cannot taken back.",
                "Spoken words cannot be taken back.",
                "Spoken words could not be taken back."
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He was attacked by a …………………… of bees.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "fleet",
                "swarm",
                "colony"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The pen is …………………… than the sword.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "stronger",
                "more powerful",
                "mightier"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The farmer owns six ……………………",
            "description": "Oxen is the plural form of ox.",
            "answers": [
                "oxes",
                "oxs",
                "oxen"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I enjoyed …………………… at the party.",
            "description": "When the subject and the object refers to the same person, the reflexive pronouns is used.",
            "answers": [
                "myself",
                "myselves",
                "me"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The teacher said to the boy, ‘You have failed again.’ Change into reported speech.",
            "description": "The present perfect in the direct speech changes into past perfect in the indirect speech.",
            "answers": [
                "The teacher said to the boy that he has failed again.",
                "The teacher told the boy that he had failed again.",
                "The teacher told the boy that he has failed again."
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If you write legibly, you ……………………… good marks.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "would get",
                "will get",
                "would have get"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "You had better ……………………. with fire.",
            "description": "After had better, the infinitive is used without to. ",
            "answers": [
                "stopped playing",
                "stopped to play",
                "stop playing"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}